Guide to the J. Martin Evans Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Teaching
  - Lectures
    - AL5 Renaissance, Rebirth - Forster and Lawrence, Contains draft, "Renaissance and Rebirth: E.M. Forster's Room with a View" (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 1: Boethius, Contains draft, "The End of the Western Empire"; handwritten chronology and notes; pamphlet of Ravenna, Italy. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - 3: Petrarch, Contains draft, "The First Romantic: Petrarch" (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Petrarch Canzoniere, Contains draft on Petrarch; supplemental passages; teaching materials from Humanities 62; hand-written notes. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - 2: Dante, Contains drafts, "Dante: The Epic of Exile" and "Dante's Comedy"; excerpts from "The Divine Comedy: Inferno"; magazine clippings; handwritten notes. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Dante, Contains draft, "The First-Person Epic: Dante's Divine Comedy"; hand-written notes. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - 4: Ariosto, Contains drafts, "Condotierri and Courtiers: Ariosto's Orlando Furioso" and "The Oresteia"; excerpt from "A Renaissance Tapestry: The Gonzaga of Mantua" by Kate Simon; biological chronologies of the Visconti, Sforza, Este rulers of Ferrara, and Gonzaga rulers of Mantua. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Talk, Contains draft, "Oxford"; materials from a lecture on Oxford and Stanford; 2005 Business Week article, "Shaking Up Oxford"; map of Oxford City Centre; hand-written notes. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - American View from Europe, 2001-2007; Contains draft; newspaper clipping; personal e-mails; handwritten notes. (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - AL3 English in Italy - Ascham to Eliot, Contains draft, "Foreigners in Florence: From the Re to the Risorgimento" (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Paris - Introduction, Contains draft, "Introduction to Paris". (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - America: The View from Europe, Contains draft, "Chapter Two: A Fool's Paradise"; list of recommended critical studies and additional primary sources; chronology of early writings about America; personal invitations from the Stanford Alumni Association. (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Bacchus, Books, Bards (1 of 2), Contains draft, "Bacchus, Books, and Bards"; hand-written notes; personal e-mails; personal invitations; magazine and newspaper clippings. (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Bacchus, Books, Bards (2 of 2), Contains draft, "Bacchus, Books, and Bards"; 1983 article from The New England Journal of Medicine, "Saturnine Gout among Roman Aristocrats"; hand-written notes; personal invitation. (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Oxford Versus Stanford, Contains draft from talk on Oxford and Stanford; list of Oxford books; magazine article, "Romancing the Stones" (on the Oxford Novel); handwritten notes. (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Cruise Lectures
      - Lectures - Cruise 4 Gallipoli (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Cruise Lectures 1 - Twain, Empty file (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Cruise 2: 3 Wine, Contains printed and hand-written materials on Italian wines (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Cruise Lecture 2 - Origo, Mala, Hogo, Contains drafts of script, "Landowners, Lieutenants, and Liberators"; supplemental images; research materials (Rome-Arno 22 January - 9 September 1944); supplemental passages. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Cruise Lecture 3 - Castiglione, Contains draft of script, "Condottieri and Courtiers" (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Cruise Lectures 4 - Boethius, Contains draft of script, "Boethius: The Consolation of Philosophy" (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Cruise Lecture - The Emperor of Elba, Contains draft of script, "The Emperor of Elba" on Napoleon; supplemental passages, maps, and pictures; travel brochures from Elba. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Odyssey
      - Odyssey - Constantinople, Contains typed script, "The Fall of Constantinople"; supplemental materials; hand-written notes; slides enclosed in plastimounts. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Odyssey - Gallipoli, Contains introductory remarks; typed script, "Gallipoli: The Victory that Almost Was"; hand-written notes; 1998 article from the New York Times International section, "Inferno of 1915: Can the Dead Hear Talk of Peace?" (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Odyssey - Greece in the Western Imagination, Contains drafts of script and hand-written notes (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Odyssey - Lepante/Rhodes, 2003; Contains chronology; research materials; script, "The Knights of Saint John"; script, "The Knights of Malta"; pamphlet for the 2003 Stanford Athens to Rome College; supplemental pictures. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Odyssey - Augustine, Contains draft of script, "Saint Augustine"; biographical sketch; supplemental passages; hand-written notes. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Piedmont
      - Piedmont - Milton, Contains draft of script, "Monastries, Massacres and Milton: Piedmont and English Literature" (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Piedmont - Cavour, 2002; Contains draft of script, "Count Camillo Cavour and the Risorgimento"; Cavour bibliography and chronology; research article on Camillo di Cavour; supplemental maps. (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Piedmont - Truffles, 2002-2006; Contains drafts of script, "White Diamonds", on Piedmont's white truffles; news and magazine articles. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Dordogne
      - Dordogne 1: Introduction A-B, Contains draft, "The Divided Dordogne: Political and Domestic Polarities" (plus earlier drafts); hand-written notes; revised draft of an essay on "The Wife of Martin Guerre" by Janet Lewis; supplemental article on "The Wife of Martin Guerre"; chronological lists on "French accounts of America" and "American accounts of France" (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Dordogne 2 - Montaigne, Contains draft, "The Multiple Self: The Essays of Michel de Montaigne"; script from a talk on Michel de Montaigne; supplemental images. (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Dordogne 3 - Black Diamonds, Contains web, newspaper, and magazine articles on white and black truffles; handwritten notes; draft, "Black Diamonds"; printout of an excerpt from "Teem - A Treasure Hunter". (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Dordogne 5 - French Conjugations, Contains draft, "Love in a Warm Climate: American Writers in France"; earlier draft, "French Conjugations: American Writers in France"; newspaper clippings of a book review on "Everybody Was So Young" by Amanda Vaill (on Gerald and Sara Murphy). (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Tuscany
      - Tuscany 1: Culture and Contrasts, Contains draft, "A Culture of Contrasts"; supplemental passage; hand-written presentation notes on index cards. (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Tuscany 6: Ongo, Contains draft, "Landowners, Lieutenants, and Liberators"; supplemental passages; 1991 article from Architectural Digest, "A Writer's Garden: Remembering Iris Origo in Tuscany"; 2003 article from The New York Times, "A Villa that Defines Tuscany"; hand-written note. (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Tuscany 2: Verrazano, Contains draft, "Place-Names, Pilots, and Polenta" on Giovanni da Verrazano; a letter written by Verrazano to Francis I; supplemental maps. (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Tuscany 4: Machiavelli, Contains draft, "The Secretary from San Casciano: Machiavelli's Prince"; list containing key dates, background reading, and related courses on "The Renaissance Crisis"; handwritten notes; Machiavelli outline. (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Tuscany 3: Boccaccio, Contains drafts, "Boccaccio"; "Town and Country Matters: Boccaccio's Decameron"; "The Divided World of Boccaccio's Decameron"; "Literature and Morality"; "Petrus Alphonsus' 'De Disciplina Clericalis'". Boccaccio outline; chronological table; handwritten notes. (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Tuscany 5: Lawrence, Contains draft, "'The Country of My Heart': D. H. Lawrence in Italy"; printouts of D. H. Lawrence poems, "A Bad Beginning" and "Spring Morning"; web article; Italian excerpt on Lawrence A. Gargnano; supplemental images. (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Tuscany 7: Forster, Contains partially complete draft of comparative essay on E. M. Forster's "Where Angels Fear to Tread" and "Room with a View"; handwritten notes; supplemental images. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Provence
      - Provence 1 - Introduction, Contains draft, "Introduction: The Land of Make-Believe"; hand-written notes. (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - Provence 2 - Petrarch, Contains Fontaine de Vaucluse tourist guide; hand-written notes on Petrarch. (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Provence 3 - Van Gogh, Contains draft, "Van Gogh"; supplemental passages, newspaper clippings, and images; hand-written notes. (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - Provence 4 - Expatriates, Contains draft, "Expatriates in Provence"; excerpts from "The Innocents Abroad" by Mark Twain and "Tender is the Night" by F. Scott Fitzgerald; San Francisco Chronicle article, "Vodka, Rubles Flowing Freely on the Riviera". (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - Provence 5 - Wine, Contains draft from a 1986 talk presented to the Stanford Seminar at the Robert Mondavi Winery, "Bacchus, Books, and Bards"; articles, "Provence and the Sunny Wines on the Riviera" and "Rhone Reds Are All the Rage"; list of white and red wines; hand-written notes; map of Chateau de Beaupre. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - IHUM Milton SA, 2002; Contains teaching materials and essays related to "Samson Agonistes" by John Milton. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - IHUM - Boethius, Contains chronology of key dates "The Disintegration of the Classical World"; draft, "The Consolation of Philosophy". (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - IHUM Milton 3, Contains draft, "Afterthoughts on Adam’s Story" (on "Paradise Lost" by John Milton). (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - The Neoclassical Epic – Milton 3 – Innocence, Contains script and outline from lecture on the state of innocence as portrayed in "Paradise Lost" by John Milton; supplemental excerpts from the Book of Genesis. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Milton Intro, 1999-2012; Contains course materials and hand-written notes from "The Poetry of John Milton" seminar. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - The Neoclassical Epic – Milton 4 – Fall, Contains materials related to a unit on "Paradise Lost" by John Milton. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Milton 1, Contains course materials from "The Poetry of John Milton" seminar; syllabi, lecture script, report topics, and hand-written notes. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - English 100J: 2 Impact of the Discovery, Contains hand-written notes; excerpts from "Second Livre des Meslanges" by Pierre de Ronsard and "Influences affecting Ronsard’s idea". (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - English 100J: 10 James, Aspern Papers, Daisy M, Contains hand-written notes and supplemental printed materials on "Daisy Miller" and "The Aspern Papers" by Henry James. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - English 100J: 8 Hawthorne’s Marble Fann, Contains notes; excerpts from biography on Nathaniel Hawthorne (chapter "England and Italy") and "Passages from the French and Italian Notebooks"; draft, "Living in the Past: American Writers in Italy". (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - English 100: 9 Twain’s Innocents Abroad, Contains hand-written notes and partially complete essays. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - English 100J: 11 James: American Scene, Contains hand-written notes; essays; research and resource materials; personal letter; excerpts from "Italian Hours" by Henry James. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Longinus (Fish), 1994-2011; Contains course materials, student essays, and hand-written notes from a unit on Longinus and "Self-Consuming Artifacts" by Stanley Fish. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - MLA – PL3 – Garden, Contains course materials from a unit on the garden as portrayed in "Paradise Lost" by John Milton; quotes, supplemental passages, hand-written notes, and student essay. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Changing Places, Contains notes on "Changing Places" by David Lodge; copy of Spring 1994 syllabus from English 42C, "The Reciprocal Vision: Our Europe, Their America". (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Henry Graham Greene, Contains course materials on Henry Graham Greene; partially complete essay drafts, printouts of online Greene biographies, excerpt from Greene’s "The Man Within", Greene outline, personal correspondence, and hand-written notes (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - English 165A: Lewis: Dodsworth, Contains materials on Sinclair Lewis and "Dodsworth"; hand-written notes, essay draft, biographical information, and class hand-outs. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - English 165 12: Kafka: Amerika, Contains notes on Kafka and "Amerika". (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - English 165A: Nabokov: Lolita, Contains hand-written notes and newspaper clippings related to Vladimir Nabokov and "Lolita". (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Professor Evans’ Lecture – Utopia, Contains course materials related to "Utopia" by Thomas More; lecture scripts and discussion notes. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Grad MLA Lycidas, Contains materials related to Henry King, Virgil’s Tenth Eclogue, and a draft on "Lycidas" by John Milton. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - MLA Comus, Contains draft on "Comus" by John Milton; Trinity handouts; list of texts related to "Comus"; handwritten notes; guidelines to Milton and Aristotle. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Milton Comus 2, Contains hand-written notes, supplemental materials to "Comus"; excerpt from "The Bridgewater Comus: Text of A Maske". (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Comus – Lecture and Notes, Contains drafts on temperance and virginity in "Comus" by John Milton; hand-written notes; student essay. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - MLA Milton – Satan, Contains copy of Stanford Course Review (1967); hand-written notes; supplemental information and references; draft on Satan as portrayed in "Paradise Lost" by John Milton; excerpt from "Milton’s Defensive God: A Reappraisal" by Gary D. Hamilton. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Literature Introduction (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Introduction English 5
      - Week 7, Lit 1 Religion (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Week 3, Identity - Essays (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Week 10, Lit & Philosophy - Floating Opera (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Week 2, Morality - Decameron (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Outlines etc. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Week 1, Preliminaries (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Week 5, Literature 1 Form (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Week 4, Lite Psychology, Hamlet (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Lit & Society: Hardy (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - MIME 03 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Poetry Selections (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - English 25
      - Milton - The Fall (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Milton: Innocence (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Mimeos (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Week 24 - Donne (1) (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Living in the Past
      - Introduction (Old) (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Intro (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Week 1 - Renaissance (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Italy (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Week 2 - Byron (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Week 3 - Browning (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Week 4 - Hawthorne (+ Jefferson) (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Week 9 - Lawrence (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Week 8 - Forster (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Week 10 - Hellenga (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Week 7 - James (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Week 6 - Howells (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Italy II (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Humanities 62
      - Week 1 - Introduction (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Week 2 - Augustine 1 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Week 3 - Augustine 2 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Week 13 - Machiavelli (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Week 5 - Ingelo Christ (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Week 4 - Boethius (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Week 6 - Beowulf (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Week 7 - Church and State (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Week 8 - Dante 1 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Week 9 - Dante 2 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Courtly Love (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Week 11 - Petrarch 1 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Week 12 - Petrarch 2 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Week 10 - Boccachio (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Week 16 - Galileo (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Week 17 - Hamlet (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Week 24 - Candide (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - English 8 Introduction (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Voltaire Candide (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - 1 HUM
      - Hamlet 1 (Box 5, Folder 49)
      - The Literature of Crisis (Box 5A, Folder 73)
      - Candide 1-2 (Box 5A, Folder 74)
      - Samson 1-3 (Box 5A, Folder 75)
      - Donne 1-3 (Box 5A, Folder 76)
      - 45 (Box 5A, Folder 77)
      - 45 - Summaries (Box 5A, Folder 78)
      - Misc (Box 5A, Folder 79)
    - 113 - The Renaissancec (Box 5A, Folder 82)
  - Undergraduate Grades + Blank Forms (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - HUM 62 Finals (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Suggestions for Final (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Humanities 62 Final Grades (Box 5A, Folder 53)
  - Milton - Masters for Biblio, Texts etc. (Box 5A, Folder 54)
  - MLA - NO (Box 5A, Folder 55)
  - Nativity Ode - Misc Notes (Box 5A, Folder 56)
  - Nativity Ode - Critisism (Box 5A, Folder 57)
  - COMUS - Textual History (Box 5A, Folder 58)
  - COMUS - Criticism and Paraphrases (Box 5A, Folder 59)
  - COMUS - Criticism: Texts (Box 5A, Folder 60)
  - Lycidas - Criticism (Box 5A, Folder 61)
  - Sonnets - Criticism (Box 5A, Folder 62)
  - Prose - Notes (Box 5A, Folder 63)
  - Prose - Criticism (Box 5A, Folder 64)
  - Undergraduate References: A-G (Box 5A, Folder 65)
  - Undergraduate References: H-P (Box 5A, Folder 66)
  - Misc. Student Files (Box 5A, Folder 67)
  - Undergraduate References: R-Z (Box 5A, Folder 68)
  - Graduate References: A-D (Box 5A, Folder 69)
  - Graduate References: P-Z (Box 5A, Folder 70)
  - Colleague References (Box 5A, Folder 71)
  - The Literature of Crisis (Box 5A, Folder 72)
  - Teaching Evals, 1971 (Box 5A, Folder 80)
  - Misc. Literature of Crisis (Box 5A, Folder 81)
  - Horace, Contains hand-written notes on Horace; student work, "Summary of Pope's 'An Essay on Criticism'"; excerpt from "The Odes of Horace". (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Marx, 1994-2004; Contains hand-written notes on Marx; Marx's poetry; student essays; supplemental images. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Sartre, 2000-2004; Contains excerpt, "Why Write?" by Jean-Paul Sartre; "Wording and Rewording" by John Carey; hand-written notes; student essays; miscellaneous files on reader interpretation. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Shelley, Contains hand-written notes on Thomas Love Peacock; student summary of the foreword to "In Defense of Reason" by Yvor Winters; excerpt, "The Four Ages of Poetry". (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Shakespeare Henry IV (1), Empty file. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Plato, Contains script from lecture on Plato; student work; hand-written notes; passage from "Inferno". (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Interpretation - Dante, Aquinas, Boccaccio, Contains hand-written notes; "Reader-Response Criticism: From Formalism to Post-Structuralism"; supplements to the work of Aquinas and Boccaccio; student essay on reader interpretation. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Aristotle, Contains hand-written notes and introduction to a script from a lecture on Aristotle; supplemental passage from "Saint Augustine Confessions"; article on Ivor Armstrong Richards; student responses to "Principles of Literary Criticism". (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Wordsworth - Subjectivity, 1995-2008; Contains "The Personal Heresy: A Controversy" essays by C.S. Lewis and E.M.W. Tillyard; student essays; excerpts from "What is an Author?" by Michael Foucault. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Wordsworth, Empty file. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Johnson, 1994-2004; Contains notes and lecture scripts related to Samuel Johnson; student essays; course materials; article, "Educating for Survival: A Call for a Core Curriculum" by Ernest L. Boyer and Martin Kaplan. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Sidney, 1994-2004; Contains hand-written notes on Philip Sidney and student essays. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Freud (1 of 2), 1995-2011; Contains student essays; article, "Freud's Theory of Dream Interpretation"; article, "Family Systems Psychotherapy, Literary Character, and Literature: An Introduction" by John V. Knapp. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Arnold, Contains hand-written notes on Matthew Arnold; poems, "The Buried Life", "Growing Old", and "The Last Word"; student work. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Eliot, 1994-2009; Contains hand-written notes on T.S. Eliot; Eliot poems; "Originality is the hallmark of great literature" and student responses; student essays; supplemental passages. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Jung, Contains hand-written notes on Carl G. Jung; "Contributions to Analytical Psychology: On the Relation of Analytical Psychology to Poetic Art"; 1982 issue from The Review of English Studies; student essays. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Feminism, 1994-2011; Contains hand-written notes on feminism and feminist criticism; Anne Howard poems; student responses to "Literary experience is always gendered"; student essays. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Freud (2 of 2), Contains hand-written notes on Freud; excerpt, "Creative Writers and Day-Dreaming" by Sigmund Freud; San Francisco Chronicle article, "Is it the Muse or mental illness?"; student essay. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Course Materials
    - Honors, Contains guide on tools for locating information and resources related to English literature; hand-written notes. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Renaissance Poetry I, 1974-1975; Contains materials from English 100 (Renaissance Literature); preliminary class list, student essays, and copies of poems ("Astrophel and Stella", "Desire", and "Splendidis Longum Valedico Nugis"). (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Honors 95, 1995; Contains materials from honors seminars; reserve lists, syllabus, end quarter reports, and student essay. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Syllabus Intro, Contains course materials from English 162 (Literary Criticism). Course adoption information, lecture scripts, class roster, hand-outs, notes, and final exam. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - The Poetry of John Milton – Student Records and Syllabi, 2001-2009; Contains course grades and copies of syllabus from "The Poetry of John Milton" seminar. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - English 25.1 Introduction, 1982-1999; Contains materials from several English courses; midterm and final examinations; syllabi; lecture scripts; reference sheet on technical terms in literature; preliminary class lists. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - English 9/109 Course Materials – Spring 2007, Contains course materials from English 9/109, "Chaucer, Shakespeare, Milton and their Contemporaries". (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Duhamel, de Sales, de Beauvoir, Contains excerpt from "America the Menace" by Georges Duhamel; excerpt from "Love in America" by Raoul de Roussy de Sales; hand-written notes on Duhamel. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - English 100J 1: Organization, 1976-2006; Contains course materials from English 100J, "The Reciprocal Vision"; syllabi; hand-written notes; quizzes; research reports; newspaper clippings; student grades. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Revel and Bruckberger, Foreword and excerpt from "Image of America" by Raymond Bruckberger; excerpt from "The American Challenge"; hand-written notes; newspaper clippings. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Living in the Past" Course Materials, 2011; Contains materials related to course, "Living in the Past: Italy in the Anglo-American Imagination"; syllabi; maps of Italy; chronology outlines; clipping of San Francisco Chronicle article, "Love, literature, leisure: Trove of Italy guidebooks". (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Course Materials, 1995-2012; Contains script from lecture on "Candide" by Voltaire and supplemental music lyrics; administrative files from various classes; class syllabi. (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Misc. Student Essays, 2003-2006 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Contains student essays; "Mark Twain and the Florentine Renaissance Humanists"; "Self and Belonging in the Anglo-American Imagination from MLA 93.
- Administration
  Student and personnel records restricted 75 years from date of creation.
  - Biblio, 2001-2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sawislak Appeal, 1998 May (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and Appointment Reviews, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Grievance, 1998 Oct (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Anthropology Proposal, 1998 Apr (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - June Flora Tenure, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Admin. Notes and Letters (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ADCOM (Box 2, Folder 7)